

Website: http://kolev.io

Email: p.kolev22@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/plamen-kolev

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/plamen-kolev-465915a7

ABOUT

My name is Plamen Kolev and I am a Newcastle, England based developer specializing in web application development, system automation and Web Application deployment. I enjoy playing with emerging technologies and stay up to date with tech trends.

In the past years, I have gained knowledge in Perl, Bash, Unix-based operating systems, python for web development and PHP.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern, Intel Corporation

August 2015 - September 2016

Worked on high-performing, cyber security projects. Created automated tests using bash, Perl and in-house tools. Developed scripts to automate product integration and deployment in a large, multi-national team

Interviewer, Populus Data Solutions

April 2014 - June 2015

Conducted national studies across Britain on sociopolitical issues

Lead Graphic Designer, Ivesto Company

September 2012 - June 2013

Worked full time as a website manager and designer where I had the opportunity to improve the user experience and maintain the two websites of the company.

EDUCATION

BSc. Computer Science, Newcastle University

September 2013 - Present

Object-oriented programing, design & development of software. Web design & construction: delivery and consumption of web content, database technologies. Computer Architecture: Parallel Computer Architectures Low-level programing. Software Engineering - principles and life cycle, scalability and maintenance. Team projects, working as part of a group.

PROJECTS

Web Platform for Digital Deployment of Virtual Servers

November 2016 - Present

Currently creating a platform for deployment, management and monitoring of virtual servers as part of final year dissertation

Technologies used: chef, bash shell, virtualbox, vagrant, ruby, ruby on rails.

Neven Body care

5 August - 28 August 2016

Created a PHP website for the neven brand, the website is deployed here. Website features internatiolization and stripe payment integration.

Secure Coding Presentation

5 May 2016

Gave a presentation in Lester College about writing code and the potential attacks that a malicious user can perform

Lloyds Banking

September 2014 - March 2015

Developed and designed a website with restful API that hooks to an Android application for the British bank Lloyds. The product was produced as part of a team.

HackNE Hackathon

31 October 2014

Co-organized a hackathon in the North East, United Kingdom backed by Major League Hacking EU. Created the website for the event, PR and print design materials.

PAConsulting

12 February 2014

Developed an environmental friendly hardware & software solution with the Raspberry Pi that involves predictive light automation and control.